





#### **SUMMARY**

Software developer with background in mobile device support and troubleshooting. Proficient with Java for Android development and database management. Excels in individual, group and leadership roles; known for building positive culture and inspiring collaboration through service leadership, effective teamwork, and strong communication skills. Experienced with remote work and collaboration through GitHub, Slack, Zoom/Webex and Asana.

### **SKILLS**

Java	Programmatic Logic	Collaborative Work
GitHub Version Control	Unit Testing	Code Documentation
Android Architecture	Critical & Creative Thinking	Attention to Detail
Relational Databases	Agile Development	Iterative Design
		· ·

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

**Deep Dive Coding @ CNM Ingenuity,** Albuquerque, NM **Java + Android Development Intern,** Jan 2020 – April 2020

Jan 2020 - April 2020

Learn principles of Object-oriented Programming, including relational database management and Android UI/UX development, and application of Scrum and Agile methods to individual and group projects.

- Choppit Individual project. Implements Jsoup and Regex to parse HTML and extract data to on-device Room database. UI incorporates XML layouts, View Model design, ReactiveX tasks, Data Binding to Recycler Adapters, Android X and Material Design components.
- Scavengr Group project. Managed workflow with Asana and remote collaboration via Slack and GitHub. Uses GMS Vision Library to interpret QR codes. Relies on communication between on-device Room database and remote Apache Derby database on a Spring/Hibernate server via prepared SQL statements to REST Controllers, handled by Okhttp3 and Retrofit 2, with Gson translation.
- Achieved proficiency with IntelliJ IDE and GitHub version control. Developed understanding of Junit5 testing, SQL queries, Gradle and Maven build/dependency systems, and object-oriented programming concepts.

Verizon Wireless, Albuquerque, NM

June 2010 - May 2019

**Technical Expert / Coordinator,** June 2018 – May 2019

Real time support and training, resolution of escalated customer concerns, and ad-hoc Supervisor duties (see below) as needed.

- Provided coaching and guidance to service reps, turning moments of uncertainty into learning experiences.
- Assisted with troubleshooting, problem-solving, negotiation, and conflict resolution, resulting in a high rate of positive responses on internal satisfaction surveys.

- Resolved escalated customer concerns directly, reaching top rank for Tech Coordinators in 4Q 2018.
- Provided support for teams whose supervisors were out of the office, maintaining motivation and accountability.

## Supervisor, June 2017 – May 2018

Support a team of 12-15 service reps. Drive performance and encourage career growth through training and development. Sustain high team morale and reinforce company culture. Manage schedules, documentation, and shifting priorities with minimal oversight.

- Iteratively designed weekly coaching sessions. Enabled reps moving from unacceptable performance to acceptable, and from acceptable to exceptional.
- Advanced employees' careers by identifying and developing their potential by creating team performance projects and targeted development opportunities.
- Built a healthy, positive, and high-performing team identity in line with company culture through collaboration, communication, and competition. Maintained team morale and cohesion through challenges including announcement of center closure.
- Created solutions to transform bulk reporting data into meaningful knowledge, using proprietary and standard software.
- Workforce management documentation and reports.

## Future Leader/Supervisor Point of Contact, June 2016 – May 2017

Learn and implemented skills including team leadership, time management, networking, and resourcefulness.

- Completed 8 weeks of self-guided training and collaborated with tenured Supervisors to observe and practice real world application. I used self-reflection, reporting data, and anonymous surveys to direct my development.
- Developed strategies to encourage positive interactions while redirecting negative attitudes constructively. Demonstrated my values and intent to employees, peers, and superiors. Earned a reputation for easily engaging employees at all levels of tenure and enthusiasm.
- Identified access-restricted applications and created innovative tools using software and physical media to replace critical resources in order to perform Supervisor duties with partial system access. I shared my solutions with my peers.

# New Hire/Transition Coach, January 2015 – June 2016

Introduce new employees to job duties and company culture.

- Delivered training in internal systems and call handling techniques. My trainees were able to consistently demonstrate the required skills and knowledge.
- Maximized new hire retention by creating a welcoming learning environment, ensuring strong team morale and fostering open communication. My teams had close to 100% retention through training

#### **EDUCATION & DEVELOPMENT**

Master of Education, Adult Education and Development, 2018 Strayer University, Online Bachelor of Arts, English, 2009 Whitman College, Walla Walla, WA Network+, 2015 CompTIA A+, 2013 CompTIA OCAJP 8, 2020 (anticipated)